<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://www.chadstovern.com/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
Chad Stovern
</title>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/
</link>
<description>
Christian. Husband. Dad. Geek.
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Sun, 01 Nov 2015 19:36:22 -0600
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/quick-tip-how-to-rename-email-flags-in-mailapp.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/quick-tip-how-to-rename-email-flags-in-mailapp.html
</link>
<title>
Quick Tip: How to Rename Email Flags in Mail.app
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Keeping email well organized is a challenge all of us face. Tags, Flags, and Inbox Zero. This short article isn't going to solve all your email woes, but will give you a quick tip to help you on your way to email nirvana.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mail.app on the Mac has a nice built in feature called Flags. Using flags helps to categorize and even note the priority of a message. Rather than keep a taxonomy floating in your head, I've written a &lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/quick-tip-how-to-rename-email-flags-in-mailapp--cms-24027'&gt;quick tutorial&lt;/a&gt; over at Tuts+ to show you how to give email flags meaningful names.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out the tutorial here: &lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/quick-tip-how-to-rename-email-flags-in-mailapp--cms-24027'&gt;Quick Tip: How to Rename Email Flags in Mail.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/build-a-20-dollar-standing-desk-in-20-minutes.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/build-a-20-dollar-standing-desk-in-20-minutes.html
</link>
<title>
Build a $20 Standing Desk in 20 Minutes
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;After nearly a decade of working jobs doing geek stuff sitting in front of a computer all day, I started developing lower back pain.  Even being active off hours wasn't enough, so I caved and talked my boss into a &lt;a href='http://www.geekdesk.com/geekdesk-v3'&gt;GeekDesk v3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, now that I've moved on and am part of a small &lt;a href='https://idonethis.com/about/our-team/'&gt;startup team&lt;/a&gt; working from my home office, that's just not a purchase I was ready to justify again.  Nine months into my new adventure with &lt;a href='https://idonethis.com'&gt;iDoneThis&lt;/a&gt; and my enthusiasm is high, yet my back is killing me…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colin, the founder of &lt;a href='http://customer.io'&gt;Customer.io&lt;/a&gt;, has an awesome and famous post about his &lt;a href='http://iamnotaprogrammer.com/Ikea-Standing-desk-for-22-dollars.html'&gt;$22 standing desk&lt;/a&gt;.  This is truly a creative gem, that I really wanted to set up for myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My problem was that my desk has a raised monitor area.  I would either have to remove part of the desk or hack off half of the back legs of the table in Colin's solution.  :-(&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/desk-sitting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Desk Sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought about finding or building a couple simple boxes as the dimensions I would need for the monitor section of my desk and the work surface were roughly the same.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After searching around for those dimensions I found this stackable &lt;a href='http://www.target.com/p/room-essentials-24-horizontal-shelf-espresso/-/A-15091670'&gt;shelf unit&lt;/a&gt; (11.63&quot; H x 24.13&quot; W x 11.63&quot; D and holds up to 20 pounds) at Target.  The total cost with tax and shipping was only $19.84 ( due to a 10% off coupon code + free in store pickup).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I brought the shelves home, it took me all of 20 minutes to clear my desk, assemble them, and set my gear back up.  I've been standing for a week now and once again my back pain has subsided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/desk-standing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Desk Standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/what-you-should-be-doing-even-when-you-dont-feel-like-it.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/what-you-should-be-doing-even-when-you-dont-feel-like-it.html
</link>
<title>
What you should be doing even when you don’t want to
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Brett Terpstra's &lt;a href='http://www.esn.fm/systematic/126'&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Rory Vaden was a gold mine, I highly recommend a &lt;a href='http://www.esn.fm/systematic/126'&gt;listen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple pull quotes in no particular order that I thought were nothing other than amazing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Successful people and top performers at some point learn to do the things they should be doing even when they don't feel like doing them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is very true.  Many of the people that inspire me, are great at this, and it's really hard to be great at doing things you just don't feel like doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Procrastination and indulgence are nothing more than creditors that charge you interest. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Relating procrastination to personal finance really resonates with me.  &quot;I'll do it later&quot; just leaves you feeling behind and you can't catch up.  Taking care of priorities before fun is one of the smartest things you can do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; The paradox principle of sacrifice: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Easy short term choices lead to difficult long term consequences.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Difficult short term choices lead to easy long term consequences.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;It's really easy to eat a cookie and grab more coffee than to go for a run and drink plenty of water each day.  :-P &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/the-importance-of-rest.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/the-importance-of-rest.html
</link>
<title>
The importance of rest
</title>
<description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Rest begets awareness. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Awareness begets prioritization. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Prioritization begets caring. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Caring begets achievement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is Eddie Smith at his &lt;a href='http://www.practicallyefficient.com/home/rest-begets'&gt;best&lt;/a&gt;.  It's also some of the best advice you can follow, but it's really hard and seems counterintuitive at times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/a-new-job-where-im-learning-to-code.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/a-new-job-where-im-learning-to-code.html
</link>
<title>
A New Job Where I'm Learning to Code
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty excited about my new job that I've been at for about three months now.  One of the great parts is the allowance for on the job time to beef up my coding skills.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote about the entire journey for our &quot;Inside iDoneThis&quot; blog; go check it out &lt;a href='http://inside.idonethis.com/learn-how-to-code/'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mindmap-dream.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dream Mindmap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/mind-mapping-101-the-visual-way-to-organize-information.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/mind-mapping-101-the-visual-way-to-organize-information.html
</link>
<title>
Mind Mapping 101: The Visual Way to Organize Information
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mindmap-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mind Map Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mind mapping is a great way to capture your thoughts and organize them visually.  By planning with a mind map you promote creative thinking and avoid forced linear thinking.  And yet, mind mapping often ends up being a buzzword, with little explanation by what it means and how you'd go about making a mind map.  I've written a full &lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/mind-mapping-101-the-visual-way-to-organize-information--cms-21182'&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; over at Tuts+ covering exactly how to get started with mind mapping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check it out here:  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/mind-mapping-101-the-visual-way-to-organize-information--cms-21182'&gt;Mind Mapping 101: The Visual Way to Organize Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/superpower-your-note-taking-skills-with-nvalt-and-simplenote.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/superpower-your-note-taking-skills-with-nvalt-and-simplenote.html
</link>
<title>
Superpower Your Note Taking Skills With nvALT and Simplenote
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/nvalt-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nvALT logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;nvALT is a powerful and fast note taking tool. It’s great for keeping running lists and creating reference documentation on–the–fly, and is absolutely essential to my daily workflow.  I've written a full &lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/superpower-your-note-taking-skills-with-nvalt-and-simplenote--cms-20816' title='Superpower Your Note Taking Skills With nvALT and Simplenote'&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; over at Tuts+ covering many tricks from tagging, markdown preview, Simplenote integration, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check it out here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/superpower-your-note-taking-skills-with-nvalt-and-simplenote--cms-20816' title='Superpower Your Note Taking Skills With nvALT and Simplenote'&gt;Superpower Your Note Taking Skills With nvALT and Simplenote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/getting-started.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/getting-started.html
</link>
<title>
Getting started
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Getting started is hard.  The best way to start when you can't seem to, is to merely start.  Being afraid to fail has claimed countless projects, blog posts, ideas, and other things from coming into existence.  I bet more often than not never starting is more of a failure than having to listen to critique, edit, make changes, or try something completely new.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;…back to writing the &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; thing &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was afraid to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/second-hand-meta-wizard.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/second-hand-meta-wizard.html
</link>
<title>
Second-hand meta wizard
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I've helped a number of people at work and elsewhere with &quot;personal productivity stuff&quot; by steering them to David Allen's book &quot;&lt;a href='ttp://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142000280/?tag=digitalnoma09-20'&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, things Merlin Mann has &lt;a href='ttp://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/47631308074/chasing-the-right-zero'&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; or said on a podcast, Scott Hanselman's talk &quot;&lt;a href='ttp://www.hanselman.com/blog/ItsNotWhatYouReadItsWhatYouIgnoreVideoOfScottHanselmansPersonalProductivityTips.aspx'&gt;Scale Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&quot; — among other resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I'm happy to be able to help others make improvements where I have also iterated and improved, I can't help but feel like sort of a &quot;Second-hand meta wizard&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I suppose all the folks listed above that have inspired me were at one point also inspired by others before them.  I guess the takeaway is summed up by a poster I like that reads &quot;Be inspired, inspire.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 10 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/a-moment-of-clarity-in-stressful-times.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/a-moment-of-clarity-in-stressful-times.html
</link>
<title>
A moment of clarity in stressful times
</title>
<description>
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;stress&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Stress&lt;/h2&gt;The past few weeks at the office have been more stressful than most.  I do fairly technical work on a regular basis and manage a small team of people at the same time.  When there are outages caused by things ranging from equipment failures to widespread fallout from &quot;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial&amp;#95;of&amp;#95;service'&gt;denial of service attacks&lt;/a&gt;&quot; online; it can quickly become a daunting task to fix problems, direct people, and manage expectations.&lt;p&gt;The problem is, this was just the most recent piece of a larger recent pattern.  I realized this when someone very close to me stated, &quot;You just don't seem happy anymore.&quot;  Now they were not saying that I don't  joke around or enjoy life — it's that my default resting state had become one that exhibits being down, worn out, and seemingly slightly depressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;clarity&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Clarity&lt;/h2&gt;It was later that afternoon after reading some texts that ended with &quot;You just don't seem happy anymore.&quot; that I had my moment of clarity.  I tweeted the following:&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sometimes it takes being in the pressure cooker beyond any level of comfort to have a moment of clarity / zen.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I then wrote the following on a small index card:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Focus on habits&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work diligently &amp; then defer / manage expectations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remain joyful (not necessarily happy)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;focus&amp;#95;on&amp;#95;habits&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Focus on habits&lt;/h3&gt;There are certain daily and weekly goals I've set to make better habits for myself.  When I don't take time to work on those goals and meet at least some of them, I can feel generally down and unhappy with myself.  It is important — daily — to spend a little time on yourself in the form of self maintenance or &quot;bettering yourself&quot; regardless of the perceived chaos you live and work in.  Find that 15 minutes a couple times a day for your own well being and sanity.&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;work&amp;#95;diligently&amp;#95;and&amp;#95;then&amp;#95;defer&amp;#95;/&amp;#95;manage&amp;#95;expectations&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Work diligently and then defer / manage expectations&lt;/h3&gt;We're made to work; it's good to exert effort and &quot;do work&quot;.  If we're taking good care of ourselves we should work diligently at what we set out to do.  For me that means working hard each day to solve problems and enlist the help of others to solve problems.  At times there are many &quot;priorities&quot; or &quot;emergencies&quot;.  We can do our best to make judgement calls and work hard, yet at the end of the day there can be an important and difficult set of responsibilities we have.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Managing the expectations of others — which often times means being ok with disappointing others in a courteous and professional manner.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Deferring what isn't complete to a future time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;remain&amp;#95;&quot;joyful&quot;&amp;#95;(not&amp;#95;necessarily&amp;#95;happy)&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Remain &quot;joyful&quot; (not necessarily happy)&lt;/h3&gt;Here's the thing about &lt;strong&gt;happiness&lt;/strong&gt;.  It &lt;strong&gt;relies on happenings&lt;/strong&gt;.  In the midst of chaos and stress I think it's important to remain &quot;joyful&quot;.  In looking at definitions &lt;a href='http://www.diffen.com/difference/Happiness&amp;#95;vs&amp;#95;Joy'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a difference between emotions that I liked:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;happiness: outward expression of elation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;joy: inward peace and contentment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me it comes down to being mindful and thankful regardless of your happenings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;in&amp;#95;summary&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In summary&lt;/h2&gt;In the midst of what seems to be overwhelming stress remember to take care of yourself (focus on habits), work hard (work diligently &amp; then defer / manage expectations), and don't let yourself get down due to your happenings (remain joyful).
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/procrastination-i-dont-think-youre-lazy.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/procrastination-i-dont-think-youre-lazy.html
</link>
<title>
Procrastination: I don't think you're lazy
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;When you see the word procrastination what do you think of?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laziness?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poor work ethic?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lack of care?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/omnifocus-completed-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;OmniFocus Completed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those things can be true — but let's face it — the fact that we're skimming an article like this this is a form of &quot;care&quot; and therefore a pretty good sign those things are mostly untrue of us.  What I believe happens more often than not is that our brain gets in the way.  I'll give you a quick example of something I've been neglecting lately, my expense report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That seems like such an easy task.  It's a task that benefits me directly, with money!  Why on earth have I not finished my last expense report?  I've seen a reminder in my &lt;em&gt;trusted system&lt;/em&gt; that tells me &quot;do expense report today&quot;.  The issue is &quot;do expense report today&quot; — while seemingly actionable — is not.  My brain knows that there are more steps to that task that I haven't defined; It's actually a project.  Maybe I know I need to print off receipts, but I have no idea where I put them.  If I don't know what the next well defined physical action is to achieve the goal of a submitted expense report, my brain provides resistance to working on it.  Let's fix this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;project&lt;/em&gt; &quot;Complete Expense Report&quot; has several physical action steps that might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find receipt from OfficeMax inbox purchase&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plot mileage from the office to our recent vendor meet-up&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find last months mileage email on my Mac to find current reimbursement rate&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Calculate mileage owed and enter into expense report spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Print cell phone receipt for on call reimbursement&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enter data for printed receipts into expense report spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Print expense report spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Attach receipts to expense report spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sign expense report and turn in to my boss&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That sounds really fancy and unnecessary Chad.  Oh really?  How many nagging things do you have on a list or floating in your head that you feel bad about because you haven't done anything about them yet?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here's my challenge to you:&lt;/strong&gt; over the next week find one thing you've been putting off that you feel is important and figure out what the first or next &lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; action is that is required to get you closer to completion.  If you do this for even one item on your todo list that isn't getting done, I promise you'll make more progress than just ocassionally thinking about it or feeling bad that it isn't done yet.  In fact, it looks like I'm all set with a set of super simple yet very well defined tasks that will lead me to finally get my latest expense report finished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
