<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://www.chadstovern.com/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
Chad Stovern
</title>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/
</link>
<description>
Christian. Husband. Dad. Geek.
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Wed, 28 Oct 2015 19:45:15 -0500
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/how-to-run-a-django-site-with-apache-mod_wsgi-and-mysql-on-freebsd-10-1.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/how-to-run-a-django-site-with-apache-mod_wsgi-and-mysql-on-freebsd-10-1.html
</link>
<title>
How to Run a Django Site with Apache, mod_wsgi, and MySQL on FreeBSD 10.1
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of developing with popular web frameworks like Django is that a lot of repetitious work has been done for you, so you can focus on building your site.  It's also great to know that the core of what you're running has undergone the scrutiny of a large open-source community and should be less susceptible to large security holes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you're a developer or not, one thing that is not inherently simple is knowing how to get these web frameworks up and running outside of your own development or testing environment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve written a &lt;a href='https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-run-a-django-site-with-apache-mod&amp;#95;wsgi-and-mysql-on-freebsd-10-1'&gt;full tutorial&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href='https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=70a5a49b1c4c'&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; covering exactly how you set this up on a FreeBSD droplet using a standard Apache, mod_wsgi, and MySQL stack running on top of FreeBSD 10.1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out the full tutorial here: &lt;a href='https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-run-a-django-site-with-apache-mod&amp;#95;wsgi-and-mysql-on-freebsd-10-1'&gt;How to Run a Django Site with Apache, mod&amp;#95;wsgi, and MySQL on FreeBSD 10.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/how-to-send-email-through-an-external-smtp-service-with-sendmail-on-freebsd-10-1.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/how-to-send-email-through-an-external-smtp-service-with-sendmail-on-freebsd-10-1.html
</link>
<title>
How To Send Email through an External SMTP Service with Sendmail on FreeBSD 10.1
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common needs when setting up a new web server is sending email. The safest and easiest way to do this is to connect your server to a mailing service such as SendGrid or Amazon SES. Using an external service will help you avoid pitfalls like your server IP getting blacklisted by anti-spam services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve written a &lt;a href='https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-send-email-through-an-external-smtp-service-with-sendmail-on-freebsd-10-1'&gt;full tutorial&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href='https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=70a5a49b1c4c'&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; covering exactly how you set this up on your FreeBSD droplet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you're new to FreeBSD, some of what we do may look a little scary, but you'll soon be comfortable rolling up your sleeves to do a little recompiling of system tools like the FreeBSD pros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out the full tutorial here: &lt;a href='https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-send-email-through-an-external-smtp-service-with-sendmail-on-freebsd-10-1'&gt;How To Send Email through an External SMTP Service with Sendmail on FreeBSD 10.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/setting-up-postgresql-on-yosemite-for-local-development.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/setting-up-postgresql-on-yosemite-for-local-development.html
</link>
<title>
Setting Up PostgreSQL on OS X Yosemite for Local Development
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I highly recommend that you download &lt;a href='https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads'&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://www.vagrantup.com/downloads.html'&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; to bootstrap a development server on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That being said there are times when you're doing a simple test or tutorial and you'd like to be able to run PostgreSQL on your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this as I found setting this up on OS X 10.10 Yosemite to be a bit of a pain, since a simple &lt;a href='http://brew.sh'&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; install didn't do the trick for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution&lt;/strong&gt;: Before going any further, this tutorial assumes you do not have a prior installation that has data you actually want to keep.  If this is not the case then &lt;strong&gt;stop now&lt;/strong&gt;, and backup your data to restore later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;fire&amp;#95;up&amp;#95;that&amp;#95;command&amp;#95;line,&amp;#95;it's&amp;#95;time&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;dive&amp;#95;in.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fire Up That Command Line, It's Time to Dive In.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not a production environment and chances are this is a Mac that you alone use.  Therefore it's perfectly acceptable to optimize for simplicity and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've never installed PostgreSQL in the past &lt;em&gt;(if you have skip ahead one step)&lt;/em&gt;, then create the data directory you need and set the permissions so your user account has full access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir /usr/local/var/postgres
chmod 770 /usr/local/var/postgres
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've installed PostgreSQL before &lt;em&gt;(if you haven't you should follow the first step and skip this one)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;do not&lt;/strong&gt; have data you care about, follow these steps to setup your data directory with full access for your user account.&lt;br /&gt; If the first command produces an error just ignore it, you're making sure PostgreSQL isn't loaded already and trying to run before you have things setup correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;launchctl unload -w &amp;#126;/Library/LaunchAgents/homebrew.mxcl.postgresql.plist
sudo rm -rf /usr/local/var/postgres
mkdir /usr/local/var/postgres
chmod 770 /usr/local/var/postgres
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now install PostgreSQL using [homebrew][].  If you already have it or an old build just uninstall that first.  &lt;em&gt;(hint: &lt;code&gt;brew uninstall postgresql&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install postgresql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next initialize the data directory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;initdb -D /usr/local/var/postgres
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the initialization is complete, setup PostgreSQL to run on boot with these two commands.  The first creates a symlink to a launch agent and the second tells launchctl that that agent would be loaded now and on boot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -sfv /usr/local/opt/postgresql/&amp;#42;.plist &amp;#126;/Library/LaunchAgents
launchctl load -w &amp;#126;/Library/LaunchAgents/homebrew.mxcl.postgresql.plist
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL will now start up and be ready to use.  One trick is to run the &lt;code&gt;createdb&lt;/code&gt; command with no arguments to create a database named after your user account.  You never have to do anything with this database, but this allows you to run the &lt;code&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt; command unadorned to connect to PostgreSQL.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR&lt;br /&gt; Do this now and save keystrokes later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;createdb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you can connect to your locally running PostgreSQL server just by running this short command.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;psql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You're now ready to create a database or two for your projects to use and start hacking.  Have fun!  :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/quick-css-for-better-looking-pull-quotes.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/quick-css-for-better-looking-pull-quotes.html
</link>
<title>
Quick CSS for better looking pull quotes
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to be one of the cool kids that could do daringfireball.net style quick pull quote + commentary posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt;  My custom theme's CSS just left pull quotes looking like plain indented text… blah, blargh, barf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't pretend to be a designer today, but I want things I make to minimize eye-bleeding whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I gave myself a timebox of 15 minutes to find a workable solution and here are the fruits of that labor:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;blockquote {
	margin-top: 25px;
	margin-bottom: 25px;
	margin-left: 50px;
	padding-left: 15px;
	border-left: 3px solid #ccc;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things can be really fun, if you let them be. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt; Me (just now, boom!)&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn more from &lt;a href='http://css-tricks.com/examples/Blockquotes/'&gt;css-tricks&lt;/a&gt; and go nuts with different classes for different uses on different parts of your site.  Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/how-to-backup-all-your-files-to-amazon-s3.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/how-to-backup-all-your-files-to-amazon-s3.html
</link>
<title>
How to Backup All Your Files to Amazon S3
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/amazon-aws.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Web Services&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Losing your favorite photos, your entire music collection, or your most important documents is something none us want to experience, yet there are still so many of us that either have an inadequate backup strategy or none at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've written a full &lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-backup-all-your-files-to-amazon-s3--cms-21386'&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; over at Tuts+ covering exactly how you can protect yourself with Amazon S3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check it out here:  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-backup-all-your-files-to-amazon-s3--cms-21386'&gt;How to Backup All Your Files to Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/upgrade-freebsd-ports-without-confirmation-prompts.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/upgrade-freebsd-ports-without-confirmation-prompts.html
</link>
<title>
Upgrade FreeBSD ports without confirmation prompts
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Here is a very handy method for updating all of the software on your FreeBSD box.  This gives you the ability to just &quot;walk away&quot; while your machine merrily hums along recompiling all your software without you having to sit around to answer prompts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;update&amp;#95;your&amp;#95;ports&amp;#95;tree&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Update your ports tree&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;portsnap fetch &amp;amp;&amp;amp; portsnap update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;check&amp;#95;for&amp;#95;updates&amp;#95;and&amp;#95;choose&amp;#95;/&amp;#95;update&amp;#95;any&amp;#95;options&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Check for updates and choose / update any options&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;portmaster -an --no-confirm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;update&amp;#95;all&amp;#95;ports&amp;#95;without&amp;#95;any&amp;#95;confirmation&amp;#95;questions&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Update all ports without any confirmation questions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;portmaster -aydbg --no-confirm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;…or&amp;#95;update&amp;#95;only&amp;#95;specific&amp;#95;ports&amp;#95;without&amp;#95;any&amp;#95;confirmation&amp;#95;questions&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;…Or update only specific ports without any confirmation questions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;portmaster -ydbg --no-confirm portdir/port portdir2/port2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;explanations&amp;#95;of&amp;#95;options&amp;#95;from&amp;#95;the&amp;#95;portmaster&amp;#95;man&amp;#95;page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Explanations of options from the portmaster man page&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;manpage&quot;&gt;-y  answer yes to all user prompts for the features below

-d  always clean distfiles

-b  create and keep a backup package of an installed port

-g  create a package of the new port

--no-confirm  
do not ask the user to confirm the list of ports to be installed and/or updated before proceeding
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/replacing-gmail-and-google-calendar.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/replacing-gmail-and-google-calendar.html
</link>
<title>
replacing gmail and google calendar
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/gmail.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gmail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll start this post by stating that I've been a Google fan for years.  I've been a Gmail user since I snagged a beta invite in college.  I followed the development of Android from before the time the G1 was announced.  I was labeled &quot;another one of those annoying people that &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to use Chrome&quot; when it was still in early single digit releases. [&lt;sup&gt;fn1]&lt;/sup&gt;  Who would be the first to quote &quot;Do no evil&quot;?  — This guy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've decided that in many facets of my life online that I'm sick of being the product and not the customer.  I am not woo'd by Google or Facebook to stay with them because of feature X or enhancement Y — no no, that focus is for the real customers — advertisers. [&lt;sup&gt;fn2]&lt;/sup&gt;  There can be real conveniences to being served relevant ad data and the US federal government is pretty much scanning everything anyway.  However, I'm at a point now where I want to more actively and consciously decide what information I'm going to give organizations.  I just want to start being the customer for once and have a little bit of personal privacy.  In this case, I'm just not ok with any of my primary forms of communication being used to target ad data to me anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;fastmail&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;the&amp;#95;rescue?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fastmail to the rescue?&lt;/h2&gt;I've looked at Opera's Fastmail offering before and have read some pretty glowing reviews about their service lately.  A couple short conversations over on App.net also sparked my interest to look into their service a bit further.  Unfortunately for my needs it's slightly cost prohibitive.  I want two email accounts each on their own domain.  A &quot;proper&quot; setup with Fastmail would cost me 80 USD per year.  I could utilize domain aliases and create some rules to bring it down to 40 USD, but I really want these accounts seperate and don't want to have to deal with the &quot;reply–as&quot; hassle with my mail applications.&lt;p&gt;After &quot;reading the rags&quot; (various forums), there have been a number of incidents where accounts were shut off for hitting send caps, or flagged and disabled for sending bulk mail out when it was not the fault of the user.  These sorts of reports — of which there were more than a few — were enough to give me pause to at least look at the rest of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;polarismail&amp;#95;+&amp;#95;icloud&amp;#95;calendars&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PolarisMail + iCloud Calendars&lt;/h2&gt;A number of people that were looking for options other than Fastmail were recommending a service called &lt;a href='ttps://www.polarismail.com'&gt;PolarisMail&lt;/a&gt;.  I'm always a bit leary of seemingly obscure recommendations.  In this case I was pleasantly surprised.  The reviews seemed to be all positive, the pricing competitive, and they even had a &quot;Fastmail Promotion&quot; running.  The promotion was designed for people unhappy with the Fastmail service and provided a 90 day free trial (up from 30) as well as a free basic mail account for every enhanced account purchased.  Their basic mail offering was only 12 USD per year per mailbox and supported multiple domains.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This means for 24 USD per year I could have the following.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two mailboxes on seperate domains yet managed from a single admin panel&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fast IMAP &amp; SMTP mail service&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A choice of webmail interfaces including the very nice looking non–free (there is no additional cost; it's just not opensource) Atmail interface&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;25 GB of storage per mailbox&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I signed up for the 30 day free trial and emailed support about the Fastmail promotion.  [&lt;sup&gt;fn3]&lt;/sup&gt;  I mentioned that I was looking to move from Google Apps to Fastmail and stumbled upon PolarisMail.  I asked if they would be willing to apply the promotion to my account for choosing them over Fastmail.  It would not have by any means been a deal breaker, but in under an hour they had responded and bumped my free trial up to 90 days.  They did also let me know that since I purchased two basic accounts and no enhanced accounts that I would not be eligible for any free accounts.  No problems there, I was just happy to see the prompt communication!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As far as calendaring goes, I've decided to use iCloud to store and sync my calendars across my devices.  I use a Mac and iPad at work and at home and I'll be moving to an iPhone soon enough.  For Android users there is an app called &quot;&lt;a href='ttps://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dmfs.caldav.icloud&amp;hl=en'&gt;SmoothSync for Cloud Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&quot; on the Play Store that will let you access and sync your iCloud calendars.  Not much else to say here other than I've had zero issues with my calendaring so far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;polarismail&amp;#95;with&amp;#95;builtin&amp;#95;caldav&amp;#95;&amp;&amp;#95;carddav&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PolarisMail with builtin CalDav &amp; CardDav&lt;/h2&gt;If you don't want to be tied to Apple for your calendaring there are options for that too.  Apple supports connecting to any CalDav or CardDav service.  Fortunately PolarisMail offers &quot;Enhanced&quot; accounts for 24 USD per year that offer those services as well.  You can look at it simply as 12 USD per year for email hosting and 12 USD per year for calendar and contact hosting and syncing.&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;buyer's&amp;#95;remorse?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Buyer's remorse?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nope.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been using the setup fo PolarisMail + iCloud calendars with my MacBook Pro, iPad, and Android phone for nearly two months now without a hiccup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to provide a tiny amount of critical feedback it would be that they still billed me after 30 days rather than a 90 day free trial.  They apologized and assured me that they would set the bill date forward for next year so I could get the extra two free months per my recommendation to keep things simple.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you're looking for an inexpensive reliable place to host your mail&lt;/strong&gt;, you should definitely consider taking &lt;a href='ttps://www.polarismail.com'&gt;PolarisMail&lt;/a&gt; for a spin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;sup&gt;fn1]:&lt;/sup&gt; Now our whole dev team uses it as their primary browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;sup&gt;fn2]:&lt;/sup&gt; Advertising isn't something I view as evil or wrong.  I merely resist it in the form of creepily parsing my personal data and building a profile to help decide which ads I see.  By contrast, I'm fine with seeing a giant Miller billboard at a Brewers game.  People that go to a stadium game are more likely to buy a beer or two, that makes sense.  Once again I would not be ok with them scanning my ticket when I purchase a brew so they could text me personalized coupon codes or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;sup&gt;fn3]:&lt;/sup&gt; The Fastmail sales folks were friendly and helpful though it did often take more than a day between replies to my short thread with them asking questions about the service and migration options.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/changing-your-internal-field-separator.html
</guid>
<link>
http://www.chadstovern.com/posts/changing-your-internal-field-separator.html
</link>
<title>
changing your internal field separator
</title>
<description>
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;wow;&amp;#95;that&amp;#95;sounds&amp;#95;pretty&amp;#95;exciting&amp;#95;doesn’t&amp;#95;it?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Wow; that sounds pretty exciting doesn’t it?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you do much shell scripting (I frequent bash) at some point you’ll come across “IFS” and learn to appreciate the usefulness in manipulating it.  Let’s look at a script showing that — and then dive into the details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env bash

## test function
ifs&amp;#95;test&amp;#40;&amp;#41;
{
	cd &amp;#126;/tmp || exit 1
	for entry in `ls -lah`
	do
		echo $entry
	done
}

## let’s see how it behaves
ifs&amp;#95;test

## let’s modify IFS and run it again
oIFS=$IFS
IFS=&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;
ifs&amp;#95;test

## let’s be anal and restore IFS explicitly
IFS=$oIFS

exit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;so&amp;#95;what’s&amp;#95;happening&amp;#95;here&amp;#95;and&amp;#95;how&amp;#95;is&amp;#95;it&amp;#95;relevant?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So what’s happening here and how is it relevant?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A number of times I’ve had to write scripts to automate the processing of files, which can turn out to be any combination of renaming them, moving them around, or checking if they are valid based on some set of rules.  One thing that can often bite me is file names with unexpected spaces.  You may say, “but people know how to name the files correctly, there’s documentation for it even.”  I’m sure you’re right, but you’re not accounting for the fact that these people are human.  Humans make mistakes.  You can get clever and pass results through another Unix tool, but I prefer to avoid extra dependencies when the shell I’m working in can handle it cleanly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an example look at the bash function &lt;code&gt;ifs&amp;#95;test&lt;/code&gt; in our example.  It’s just a trivial for loop which echoes out the results of the &lt;code&gt;ls -lah&lt;/code&gt; command.  The first time it is called this is the result we get:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;chadhs@mac scratch&amp;#93;$ ./ifstest.sh
drwxr-xr-x
4
chadhs
staff
136B
Mar
24
19:36
.
drwxr-xr-x+
39
chadhs
staff
1.3K
Mar
24
19:36
..
-rw-r--r--
1
chadhs
staff
576B
Jul
31
2012
pckeyboardhack.tmp
-rw-r--r--
1
chadhs
staff
0B
Mar
24
17:17
so-secret-filename-is-classified.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ouch.&amp;#95;&amp;#95;that&amp;#95;was&amp;#95;super&amp;#95;ugly;&amp;#95;how&amp;#95;do&amp;#95;we&amp;#95;fix&amp;#95;it?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ouch.  That was super ugly; how do we fix it?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before explaining that, let’s see how the output looks the second time the function &lt;code&gt;ifs&amp;#95;test&lt;/code&gt; is called.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;drwxr-xr-x   4 chadhs  staff   136B Mar 24 19:36 .
drwxr-xr-x+ 39 chadhs  staff   1.3K Mar 24 19:36 ..
-rw-r--r--   1 chadhs  staff   576B Jul 31  2012 pckeyboardhack.tmp
-rw-r--r--   1 chadhs  staff     0B Mar 24 17:17 so-secret-filename…
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ahh…&amp;#95;that’s&amp;#95;much&amp;#95;better.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ahh… that’s much better.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So to fully understand what is going on each time the function &lt;code&gt;ifs&amp;#95;test&lt;/code&gt; is called we need to understand what the variable IFS is.  By default the internal shell variable IFS is set to recognize spaces, tabs, and new lines as a field delimiter (aka Internal Field Separator).  Seeing that there are multiple spaces in each of our results from the &lt;code&gt;ls -lah&lt;/code&gt; command in the for loop, our shell is treating every single white space (compare the first result to the second) as a delimiter for a new item in our list of results renerated in the for loop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;now&amp;#95;for&amp;#95;the&amp;#95;fix&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Now for the fix&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice in our example that before the function &lt;code&gt;ifs&amp;#95;test&lt;/code&gt; is called the second time, we set a variable called oIFS to store the default value of IFS, and then change IFS to only treat a new line as a field separator / delimiter.  Once we no longer need this behavior we then set IFS back to it’s default value [&lt;sup&gt;unset].&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;wrapping&amp;#95;it&amp;#95;all&amp;#95;up&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Wrapping it all up&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason I spent a little time writing this up and sharing it was the simple fact that learning about how to alter IFS to control how the shell delimits results saved me some pain in a project recently.  My scripts continued to run and do their job but I’d get a lot of little errors when someone didn’t follow the documentation; and trusting humans is just bad for business.  ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;sup&gt;unset]:&lt;/sup&gt; In theory we can just unset IFS to return it to it’s default value, but I like to do it manually &amp; explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
